I think data is actually really exciting.
أعتقد أن البيانات شيقة جدًا.
I feel like data is really just information.
أشعر أن البيانات هي فقط معلومات.
And so, the more information that you have,
وهكذا، فإنه كلما زادت معلوماتك،
the better decision that you can make.
كلما اتخذت قرارًا أفضل.
My name is Sinthuja, and I'm a Manager of Data Analytics at Summit Public Schools.
اسمي سينثوجا، وأنا مديرة تحليل البيانات في Summit Public Schools.
I've actually had a few different roles.
في الواقع، لقد شغلت بعض المناصب.
I worked a little bit in consulting and then decided to be a teacher.
عملت قليلًا في الاستشارة ومن ثم قررت أن أصبح معلمة.
And data was actually, just seemed like the perfect fit for me,
ولقد كانت البيانات في الحقيقة تبدو أنها الموائم المثالي لي،
because it makes my previous teaching experience,
لأنها تتوافق مع خبرتي التدريسية السابقة،
at working in an education company,
عند عملي في شركة تعليمية،
with also a more technical aspect as well.
بالإضافة إلى جانب تقني أيضًا.
So, Summit public schools is actually a charter management organization, a nonprofit,
لذا فإن مدارس القمة العامة هي مؤسسة إدارية عظيمة، غير ربحية
and we have developed
ولقد قمنا بتطوير
our own platform that we partnered with the Chan Zuckerberg initiative.
منصتنا الخاصة بالاشتراك مع مبادرة Chan Zuckerberg.
They store all the student grades data
إنهم يقومون بتخزين جميع بيانات علامات التلاميذ
and also how they're interacting with the platform,
وكيفية تفاعلهم مع المنصة،
in that database, and that's really what we use to analyze.
في قاعدة البيانات تلك وهذا ما نستخدم للتحليل.
One of the projects that I'm really excited about is
إن أحد المشروعات التي أهتم بها كثيرًا هو
analyzing and tracking student performance data,
بيانات تحليل وتتبع الأداء الطلابي
and actually building tools for school leaders and teachers in
وبناء الأدوات لرواد المدرسة والمعلمين في
tableau and displaying that data for them to use on a weekly or daily basis.
tableau وبعرض هذه البيانات عليهم لاستخدامها بشكل يومي أو أسبوعي.
I've actually had the privilege of doing focus groups
لقد كان لدي الأسبقية في عقد مجموعات تركيز
and user experience interviews with school leaders and teachers to
ومقابلات تتناول خبرات المستخدم مع رواد المدرسة ومعلميها
develop an experience that they can really use to improve outcomes of their schools.
لتطوير خبرة يمكنهم استخدامها بالفعل لتحسين ناتج مدارسهم.
I've seen Summit grow from both a small organization to a large,
لقد رأيت Summit تنمو من خلال مؤسسة صغيرة إلى أخرى كبيرة،
and even when you're small you have to figure out a lot of things on your own of like,
وحتى إذا كنت صغيرًا يجب عليك اكتشاف العديد من الأشياء بحسب تفضيلك لها،
how the data is structured and being able to analyze it in the correct way.
كيفية بناء البيانات والتحلي بالقدرة على تحليلها بشكل صحيح.
But once we built the data infrastructure,
ولكن بمجرد بناءنا للبنية التحتية للبيانات،
you still have to really be able to like think about questions on your own,
ينبغي عليك التحلي بالقدرة على التفكير عن أسئلة حول
and lead projects, and ask what's the next step that I want to do with this analysis.
مشروعاتك الشخصية والمشروعات الرائدة، وتسأل عما تكون الخطوة التالية التي أود القيام بها في هذا التحليل.
So, I think dealing with ambiguity is going to be a key part of any data analyst role.
لذلك، إنني أعتقد أن التعامل مع الغموض سيكون الجزء الرئيسي لدور أي مُحلل بيانات.
I think as long as you have like a good foundation in SQL,
أعتقد أنه كلما كان لديك هيئة جيدة مثل SQL،
and then also some statistical background,
ثم تأتي بعض الخلفية الإحصائية
whether that could be in Python, in R,
التي يمكن أن تكون في n Python،في R، أو Stata
or Stata, like all of
كجميع
those languages will really set you up to be a successful data analyst.
تلك اللغات التي ضبطناك على استخدامها لتكون محلل بيانات ناجح.
And it's really just understanding a data infrastructure and
إنه فقط يدور حول فهم البنية التحتية للبيانات
how your data systems are set up,
وكيفية ضبط أنظمة بياناتك،
and then being able to join everything and just
ومن ثم القدرة على الانضمام لكل شيء
aggregate and analyze in a way that makes sense.
وتجميعه وتحليله بشكل ملموس.
One of the key things that I've learned is that there is always something new to learn.
إن إحدى الأشياء الأساسية التي تعلمتها هي أن هناك دائمًا شيئًا جديدًا لتتعلمه.
So, even though I feel like I've developed a lot of skill in SQL and Python,
لذلك، فبالرغم من أنني تطورت العديد من المهارات في SQL وPython
I'm always trying to figure out what's like
فإنني أحاول دائمًا أن أكتشف كيف سيكون
the next thing that I can learn to improve my skill set.
الشيء التالي الذي أستطيع تعلمه لتحسين مجموعة مهاراتي.
I've tried a lot of different programs in order to increase my skill set, and yeah,
جربت العديد من البرامج المختلفة كي أزيد من مجموعة مهاراتي وأجل،
my favorite course has actually been one of the courses that I took on Udacity,
لقد كانت دورتي التدريبية المفضلة هي إحدى الدورات التدريبية التي أخذتها على Udacity،
mainly because of the project based learning.
يرجع هذا بشكل رئيسي إلى التعلم القائم على المشاريع.
I think that online learning is great,
أعتقد أن التعلم عن طريق الإنترنت شيء عظيم،
and like you can delve into topics on your own pace,
حيث يمكنك التعمق أكثر في الموضوعات بحسب رغبتك،
but actually being able to apply it,
ولكن كيفية تطبيقها حقًا
is really where you learn a lot,
هو حيث يمكنك التعلم أكثر
and you learn what you know,
وأنت تتعلم ما تعلم
what you don't know,
وما لا تعلم
and also it just really stretches your thinking in a different way, and so,
كما انها أيضًا توسع مدارك عقلك بشكل مختلف ومن ثم
Udacity's courses where they force you to kind of do that project at
فإن الدورات التدريبية في Udacity هي حيث تدفعك إلى شكل من إنجاز المشروع
the end of the unit are actually super beneficial and I would highly recommend them.
في نهاية الوحدة، وهذه ذي منفعة كبيرة وأوصي بها كثيرًا.
I think that the data analysts role is going to be an integral part of any company,
أعتقد أن دور محللي البيانات سيكون جزء تكاملي من أي شركة،
as our society has so much access to data and it's only going to continue to grow.
وحيث إن مجتمعنا قد وصل بشكل كبير إلى البيانات فإنها ستستمر فقط في النمو.
That if you have a data analyst background,
فإذا كانت لديك خلفية تحليل بيانات،
it really will set you up to be successful in any types of roles that you have later on.
سيضبطك هذا على النجاح في عدة أنواع وأدوار ستلعبها لاحقا.